<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: HD | Furthburners and related widgets.]]></title>
  <link href="http://furthburner.github.io/blog/categories/hd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://furthburner.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-21T14:46:31-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://furthburner.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Furth Burning Man]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ditch Cable. Enjoy Free OTA HDTV With an Antenna and a Booster. Save $.]]></title>
    <link href="http://furthburner.github.io/blog/2014/01/16/ditch-cable-enjoy-free-ota-hdtv-with-an-antenna-and-a-booster-save-%24/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-16T22:23:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://furthburner.github.io/blog/2014/01/16/ditch-cable-enjoy-free-ota-hdtv-with-an-antenna-and-a-booster-save-$</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, you  want to enjoy  TV programming minus  the trouble and  the expenses of  paying for
cable TV. If you live in the USA, you are in luck—my short note below will help you choose
and install a simple antenna system that will get the TV signals to your TV. Hope you have
a HDTV—these instructions will only work for HDTVs.</p>

<p>The very first  step is to check if  your address has decent TV reception.  The website <a
title="AntennaWeb                 website"                href="http://www.antennaweb.org"
target="_blank"><a href="http://www.antennaweb.org">http://www.antennaweb.org</a></a> will let  you check if you can  get any Over
The Air (OTA) reception for any of the  channels at your address. Hopefully, you get a few
channels, and you can actually rid your home  of a cable subscription. The next step is to
get an antenna. There are a large number of HDTV antennas out there, but I currently use a
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mohu-Leaf-Paper-Thin-Indoor-Antenna/dp/B004QK7HI8">Mohu Leaf antenna</a>, which
is   quite  discreet.   Until recently, I used  an  <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Antennas-Direct-DB2-Directional-Antenna/dp/B000EHUE7I/ref=sr_1_2?s=electronics&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1328403643&amp;amp;sr=1-2">Antennas Direct DB2</a>, which  was
 far bulkier, uglier  but about as good. Depending  on where you
live,      you      may      need      a      signal     booster—I      use      a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Antennas-Direct-DB2-Directional-Antenna/dp/B000EHUE7I/ref=sr_1_2?s=electronics&amp;amp;ie%0A=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1328403643&amp;amp;sr=1-2">Motorola bi-directional RF amplifier</a>, but I have also used a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B000F28DP2/ref=pe_385040_30332190_TE_M3T1_ST1_dp_1">PCT 1-port bi-directional cable TV/HDTV amplifier signal booster with passive return path</a>
 and works just as well.</p>

<p>Install the antenna and RF amplifier close to the TV. My antenna is right beside my HDTV—I
didn&rsquo;t bother  hanging the antenna outside  and running coax  all the way to  my TV—though
with the Antennas Direct DB2 antenna model, though I could have. However, if I did that, I
will probably have  had to amplify the signal  a couple of times before it  reaches the TV
(one signal booster per 75 feet of coax is a rule I read somewhere on the Internet).</p>

<p>The next step is to tune your TV to receive the channels your antenna is pushing. Many TVs
have   an   autotune   feature   for   antennas.   On  my   Panasonic   TV,   you   choose
Menu-&gt;setup-&gt;auto tune, and bingo, the TV  automatically tunes itself for all the TV
programming it is picking up via the antenna.</p>

<p>Thats' it! You are done! No more pesky monthly cable bills for your TV, and no more yearly
arbitrary bill increases.</p>

<p>When you enjoy your TV programming via the antenna, be prepared to experience minor signal
disruptions every once a while, but mainly when the weather goes bad. Where I live, in New
England, I find the  signal disruption happens when it rains, and  when it snows, but also
sometimes when the weather  is perfect. On the whole, I don&rsquo;t  experience it very often at
all—say a handful of  times in a year. When the disruptions do occur,  get a sense of what
signal strength  the TV is experiencing—this  information has a direct  correlation to the
quality of the signal, and the disruptions you see (on my Panasonic TV, this is an item on
the  sub-menu). Most  often, minor,  5-10 degree  change in  antenna direction  solves the
problem for me.. Considering  the fact that my setup is in the  basement with no access to
the exterior around, this is remarkable.</p>

<p>I bought my OTA HD antenna goodies from  Amazon a few years ago when the analog TV signals
were beginning to be phased out (2008).  At that time, the total cost of my antenna+signal
booster for OTA HDTV were about $80 US. Since then, I&rsquo;ve upgraded to the Mohu leaf antenna
which is extremely discreet  but just as good as my previous  antenna (my wife argues that
it is better). The total cost of TV  programming for our household over the past 6 years =
USD 120  (two antennas including  the recent upgrade,  and a signal booster).  Total saved
(assuming USD  10 per  month for  basic cable): USD  12 x  10 x  6 &ndash; USD  120 =  USD 600).
Everyone knows that cable companies charge more for basic channels, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
