<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Google voice | Furth burners and related widgets.]]></title>
  <link href="http://furthburner.github.io/blog/categories/google-voice/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://furthburner.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-10T11:35:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://furthburner.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Furth Burning Man]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Want a landline phone? Set up a completely free landline service]]></title>
    <link href="http://furthburner.github.io/blog/2014/01/16/want-a-landline-phone-set-up-a-completely-free-landline-service-for-us-and-canada/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-16T22:13:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://furthburner.github.io/blog/2014/01/16/want-a-landline-phone-set-up-a-completely-free-landline-service-for-us-and-canada</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here in the North  America, it must truly be one of the  most crazy market observations of
the day that there are people who actually pay for their non-mobile telephone service, the
kind of service that until just a few years ago, used to be called a “landline.”</p>

<p>The landline lives among us. It lurks in all manner of deals, triple-plays, dual-plays and
quad-plays; disguised  as a service you need  to pay for. “$20  unlimited US/Canada!” “$20
Unlimited world” (by  “world,” they only mean “US/Canada and  three other countries). All
manner of other bizarre promotions exist.</p>

<p>But my question is—if you live in the US and Canada—why on earth would you want to pay for
telephone service in an era when Google  Voice exists, and there are a zillion ATA devices
out there? I enjoyed  free phone calling goodness for all 2011  through 2013, and in 2014,
it appears like  Google has every intention  of keeping Google voice payment  free for USA
and Canada calls.</p>

<p>In the “good-old days” age of telephony, PSTN-based telephone companies were all the rage,
and they needed physical telephone wires to be laid all the way into your home. This means
that the  cost of  the telephone service  was to p  ay for  the labor, maintenance  of the
cabling  to  your home  and  your  neighbors' and  the  infrastructure  that  needs to  be
maintained at the core. The great side effect of the Internet-based transport of telephony
data (or VoIP)  is th at the rapidly expanding  infrastructure for Internet communications
laid by  the same  companies that  are selling you  “landline” plans  can also  carry your
telephony data. Psst: here&rsquo;s  a dirty secret: that is precisely what  these co mpanies are
doing when you pay them for a “landline—“  you are not exactly using a telephone wire very
much any more.</p>

<p>My question is: why are you letting them do that?</p>

<p>I have  been using free phone  service via Google  Voice and my regular,  “landline” phone
devices (Uniden phones or even an old fashioned  corded one!) for nearly a year now, and I
was a late entrant  to this party! It is possible through the magic  of an ATA device like
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/OBi110-Service-Bridge-Telephone-Adapter/dp/B0045RMEPI">ObiHai   110</a>
and a  Google Voice account,  which is free,  and already available to  you if you  have a
Google mail account on gmail (that is, no  additional crap to sign up for and maintain the
password). I spent a  total of $50 USD circa spring of 2011 on  the ObiHai 110 device, and
powered it  up and connected  it to via Ethernet  to m y  router in the basement.   I also
connected a  “landline” cordless phone&rsquo;s base  to the phone  (RJ11) port on my  ObiHai 110
using a telephone  jack. I then <a href="http://obihai.com/googlevoice.html">configured the  ObiHai 110 device to use  my Google Voice
account  details</a>. Lo and  behold! I  now have  a dial
tone on  my landline device,  and you  can use your  cordless phone to  make/receive phone
calls in the USA and Canada.</p>

<p>Yes, it is really that simple!</p>

<p>Do it!</p>

<p>PS: There&rsquo;s  just one caveat to  all of this&mdash;you cannot  make 911 calls with  the setup I
describe above. Rather,  for making 911 calls, you have to  register with an old-fashioned
phone company  and pay only  for their 911  service (don &rsquo;t you  just hate that!).  Read a
<a href="http://michigantelephone.wordpress.com/2011/01/25/review-of-the-obihai-obi110-voip-device-part-3-911-on-the-cheap/">crisper         introduction         to         some        hacks         on         this
front</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
